

## Skills

## Top 1% Contributor on Stack Overflow Exceptional Achievements in the **Programming Community**

JavaScript/TypeScript (> 9 years)

Web, Desktop, and Mobile Applications (React, Vue, Angular, Svelte)

**\* \* \* \* \*** 

C# Development (> 20 years)

Web, Desktop, Server, and Mobile **Applications** 

APIs (> 15 years)

GraphQL & REST APIs **\* \* \* \* \*** 

SQL Databases (> 9 years)

PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server,

MariaDB, MySQL, SQLite  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

NoSQL Databases (> 15 years) MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

DevOps (> 9 years)

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

GitLab

Serverless (> 9 years) AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,

**Azure Functions** 

Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions,

Spoken Languages

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \diamond \diamond$ 

Edge Computing (> 1 year) Edge Functions & Edge Runtime

German

**English** 

## **Denis Knaack**

Software Development & Consulting

& +49 170 5867448 • @ denis@knaack.it • ♂ https://www.knaack.it

**Profiles** 

in /denisknaack

/dknaack

/knaackee

Okt. 2003 – Jan. 2008

Jan. 2008 – Apr. 2011

Nov. 2012 - Feb. 2015

Steinberg am See, DE

Regensburg, DE

Regensburg, DE

2000 - 2003

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

**Typescript** 

NodeJS / Typescript

Throughout my career, I have worked with various programming languages, tools, and services. My passion for technology motivated me to continually evolve. Customers appreciate my ability to integrate new technologies and provide solutions that often exceed their objectives.

As the CTO and co-founder of a startup, I gained valuable insights into business life. I use these experiences to advise teams and develop strategies that align with business goals. In this role, I was also involved in the creation and acquisition of a software patent.

Professional Experience GoNamic GmbH

Manager Software Development Regensburg, DE

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG Manager Software Development

Regensburg, DE Apr. 2011 - Nov. 2012 SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

Omniga GmbH & Co. KG

Senior Manager Software Development

Software Development Professional

Software Development & Consulting

KNAACK.IT Feb. 2015 - heute

Education

Fintech Startup

Distribution)

BSZ Matthäus Runtinger BSIII Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung (IT Specialist in

Application Development)

Projects (Excerpt)

Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech startup, utilizing C#

and Microsoft SQL Database. Automated Email Dispatch (Implementation of Automated Invoice Email

Implementation of an automated system for emailing invoices, developed in

Visa Policy Update C# Implementation of new requirements for visa payment processing using C#.

Website Relaunch

Redevelopment and modernization of a website using C#. **Password Validation** 

Transition from plain text passwords to hashed and salted passwords,

implemented in C#. Mailgun Integration

Implementation and documentation. Consulting GraphQL

Advising a development team on GraphQL implementation and best practices.

GraphQL Backend

Plug-In System

React and TypeScript.

developed in TypeScript.

and TypeScript.

Figma.

Development of a sample implementation for a GraphQL backend using NodeJS and TypeScript.

**NNTP Client** 

Development of an NNTP client using C#.

Enhancement of a Windows client with a plug-in system, developed in C#.

Auto-Updater C# Implementation of an automatic update system for a Windows application.

COVID Scanner App **React Native** 

Creation of an app for scanning and displaying information from QR codes,

developed with React Native. **Marketing Website** React / Typescript

Development of a website for a mid-sized company, utilizing React and TypeScript.

Al Chatbot React / Typescript Design and integration of an AI chatbot based on ChatGPT, implemented using

UI / UX Figma

Automatic Update Feature for Electron App **NodeJS** 

Creation and presentation of a user interface for a web application using

Development of a self-updating mechanism tailored for an Electron application, utilizing NodeJS.

GraphQL Backend NodeJS / Typescript Development of an API with integration to a PostgreSQL database,

implemented using NodeJS and TypeScript. **Chrome Extension** 

Development of a Chrome extension with ChatGPT integration, implemented in TypeScript.

**Outlook Plugin** Typescript Creation of a plugin for easier management of filters and folders in Outlook,

NodeJS / Electron / Typescript **Desktop Client** 

Development of a cross-platform client for Windows, Mac, and Linux for processing and analyzing AAF files, using NodeJS, Electron, TypeScript, and C#.

CI / CD Github Actions Creation and implementation of a Continuous Integration and Continuous

Delivery (CI/CD) process for a team with various projects, utilizing GitHub Actions.

Development of a Progressive Web App (installable, offline-ready) with

React / Typescript **Progressive Web App** features including authentication, email sending, and more, built using React